PETER CHUZIE

pchuzi50@lakers.mercyhurst.edu
724-372-5270

EDUCATION

Grove City Area High School 2016

Mercyhurst University

Bachelor of Arts Intelligence Studies 2020

SUMMARY

I am a sophomore at Mercyhurst University pursuing a degree in Intelligence Studies. I have been expanding my intelligence analysis experience by working on a contract with businesses through Ridge College CIRAT as well as focusing deeply on my studies to refine my analysis skills. My skills of leadership and critical thinking have been increasing developed through my job in the Intelligence IT department as well as being a resident assistant for Mercyhurst University. I have a passion for learning that is coupled with my ability to learn quickly, which I feel will help me to excel in the field of intelligence and IT.

EMPLOYMENT

MERCYHURST UNIVERSITY

Student and facility IT technician
Assist students and facility with IT related issues.

Mercyhurst University Ridge College Jan 2017 to Current

CIRAT

Analyst May 2017 to Aug 2017

Contracted through the Tom Ridge School of Intelligence to a competitive intelligence firm that specializes in providing global human intelligence (HUMINT) field collection and analysis systems.

Responsible for daily monitoring of news relevant to several different business units, and production and dissemination of daily intelligence products to relevant decision makers using cutting edge data mining technology.

PROJECTS

COUNTRY STUDY: ROMANIA

May 2017

Used structured analytical techniques and open-source information to analyze its stability.

IN DEPTH STUDY OF NORTH KOREA

Aug 2017 to Current

Tasked to understand North Korean government structure and profiling leaders to analyze its stability by the end of 2018.

AWARDS

Meryhurst University · DEANS LIST

Fall 2016

Mercyhurst University · DEANS LIST

Spring 2017

Recognition of academic excellence

Recognition of academic excellence

Grove City Area School District · JIGGS WOLFORD AWARD

Fall 2015

A leadership award presented to a senior athlete, voted on by the players.

The Rotary Club · ROTARY YOUTH LEADERSHIP AWARD

Jun 2015

Four people are selected from Grove City Area High School to attend a week long camp focused on leadership skill building at Westminster College.

ACTIVITIES

THE COMPUTER TRACK CLUB · Secretary

Spring 2017

RESIDENT ASSISTANT

Aug 2017 to Current

An assistant to help freshman transition into their first year of college.

ASSET MANAGEMENT CLUB · Member

Fall 2017 to Current

A club focused on understanding the market and investing.

GUI'S KIDS CAFE · Volunteer St. Mary's School Erie, PA

VOLUNTEERING

Fall 2017 to Current

Engaged with children of Erie in after school programs.

EMMAUS SOUP KITCHEN · Volunteer

Erie, PA

Spring 2017

BELOVED DISCIPLE CHURCH \cdot Alter Server/ Eucharistic Minister/ Vacation Bible School Staff Grove City, PA

2009 to Current

EQUESTRIAN THERAPY CAMP · Volunteer

2013 to 2014

Slippery Rock University, PAAssisted autistic campers with horse riding for a therapeutic experience.